Finding Aid for Michigan Organization for Human Rights Records 1970-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audiotapes, 1973-1980, 83 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes
  - Gayly Speaking (Radio program)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Poetry of Jeff Sarrasson (#98), 1975 July 17, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-146-1]; mp3 file; (Reading of poetry by Jeff Sarrasson. Poems read are: "of closets and puberty", "recess", "sixteen (xvi)", "euthanasia", "for the guys", "the emperor's clothes", "having just performed an act from which she derived no pleasure, a constructive", "headline: Frederic Jennings jr. fiance to miss giglio", "several are sitting in a shallow basin where they are in liquid." Engineer is Bob Stanton.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] With Downcast Gays (#100), 1975 July 31, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-147-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. No announcers or engineers are listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay Pride Week Review (#96), 1975 July 03, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-148-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. No speakers listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Kinsey Report (#104), 1975 August 28, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-149-1]; mp3 file; (Includes cue sheet for engineers. Speakers are not listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Oppression (#90), 1975 May 22, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-150-1]; mp3 file; (Includes cue sheet for engineers. Speakers listed are: Martin Mass, Stuart Michaels, and Michael Rutz. Producer listed is Greg Turner.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Periodicals (#110), 1975 October 09, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-151-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. No performers are listed, engineer is listed as Bob Stanton.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Book Discussion: Out of the Closets (#114), 1975 November 06, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-152-1]; mp3 file; (Includes engineer's cue sheet in tape box. Producers and speakers are not listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Magazine (#118), 1975 December 04, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-153-1]; mp3 file; (Includes cue sheet and list of content by timestamp in tape box. Speakers listed are Farber, Sarasson, and GRC.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Poetry of Don Mager (#120), 1975 February 18, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-154-1]; mp3 file; (Gayly Speaking Radio Program of Don Mager's poetry.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Radical Left (# 124), 1976 January 15, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-155-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. No announcers or producers listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay Switchboard (#126), 1976 January 29, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-156-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Engineer listed is Bob Stanton.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Magazine (#128), 1976 February 12, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-157-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes cue sheet and list of content and announcers scripts.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Directions of Gay Movement (#130), 1976 February 26, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-158-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes cue sheet for WDET-FM. Speakers, announcers, and engineers are not listed.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Magazine: Book Review of "Homosexual Matrix", Profile of Gay Pride Week Committee, Music, and Listener Response (#132), 1976 March 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-159-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Speakers listed are: Will Hollis, Greg Turner, Bob Stanon, John Evola, and David Krumroy who is also listed as producer.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Therapy (#134), 1976 March 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-160-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Announcers listed are Greg Turner, Bob Stanton, Lemay, Gershow, and Krumroy.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Call-in (#136), 1976 April 08, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-161-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Speakers listed are Greg Turner, Robert Roxi, Heather Anderson, Brian McNaught.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Magazine: After UR Out (#138), 1976 April 22, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-162-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes a script for announcers and speakers. Speakers listed are Don Mager, David Krumroy, and Greg Turner. References books by Karla Jay and Allen Young.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Matlovitch at Dignity (#142), 1976 May 20, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-163-1]; mp3 file; (Recorded May 18, 1976. Matlovitch at Dignity; ASP; Boys of Boise. Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Lynn, Bo, and Bill are listed as announcers.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Best of Gayly Speaking; Gay Pride Week (#146), 1976 June 17, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-164-1]; mp3 file; (Selections from the first two and half years of Gayly Speaking.)
      - [Part 2], [85287-SR-164-2]; mp3 file; (Selections from the first two and half years of Gayly Speaking. Short three minute clip discussing the Association of Suburban People.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay Spirit (#154), 1976 August 12, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-165-1]; mp3 file; (Greg's Goodbye; Gay Spirit. First ten minutes of the program are music recordings. Discussing the book "Gay Spirit.")
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Ralph and Alfred, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-166-1]; mp3 file; (Radio dramatization program discussing Christmas lists and shopping.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Troy Perry (#158), 1976 September 01, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-167-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes cue sheet. No speakers or producers listed. Includes music reviews and a political speech from Troy Perry.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] V.D.: Book reviews (#160), September 23,1976, 1976 September 23, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7.5
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-168-1]; mp3 file; (Tape box includes engineer's cue sheet. Speaker is listed as John Evola. Book reviews by Will Hollis, poetry readings, a discussion and advice on sexually transmitted infections.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Readings, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-169-1]; mp3 file; (Announcer discusses the phenomenon of "cruising" and dynamics of male sexuality. )
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Speeches (Militant Forum), 1974 June 28, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-170-1-1]; mp3 file; (No. 5977, recorded June 28 at the Militant Forum entitled "Christopher Street: Five Years Out of the Closet." Speakers are Don Mager, Kathy Kovachenko, and Rachel Fruit.)
      - [Part 2], [85287-SR-170-1-2]; mp3 file; (No. 5977, recorded June 28 at the Militant Forum entitled "Christopher Street: Five Years Out of the Closet." Speakers are Don Mager, Kathy Kovachenko, and Rachel Fruit.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay Switchboard, 1976 December 30, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-171-1]; mp3 file; (Announcements and news to the LGBT community in Detroit and a discussion of Gay History.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Living Alone (#178), 1977 January 27, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-172-1]; mp3 file; (Don Mager is announcing with news, announcements, and gay history. Panel Discussion on "Living Alone.")
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay History (#182), 1977 February 24, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-173-1]; mp3 file; (Discussing Gay History and the work of German Gay Historians.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Don Mager and John Buckstaff on Obscenity, 1977 April 07, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-174-1]; mp3 file; (Tape is labeled "Living Alone, #178" Content matches description for item title. Don Mager and John Buckstaff, WDET Station Manager, discussing obscenity and free speech in radio and broadcasting.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] [Unidentified] (#170), 1976 December 02, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-175-1]; mp3 file; (Father John McNeil, author of "The Church and the Homosexual" interviewed by Larry Lee interview. Discussion of magazine "Gay Left", with Stuart Michael, Don Mager on Gay History, part three.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Homosexual by Sexual (#162), 1976 October 07, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-176-1]; mp3 file; (Discussing married men who identify as gay men as well a discussion of gay history.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Theme Music, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-177-1-1]; mp3 file; (Theme Music for the Gayly Speaking radio program: "Night in the City", "You Can Laugh", "Waiting Lady", "Flower Man", "My Party." Life call-in show open to questions and comments from the public. Guests are from the Association of Suburban People (ASP), Phil Green and Dan Seville.)
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-177-1-2]; mp3 file; (Theme Music for the Gayly Speaking radio program: "Night in the City", "You Can Laugh", "Waiting Lady", "Flower Man", "My Party." Life call-in show open to questions and comments from the public. Guests are from the Association of Suburban People (ASP), Phil Green and Dan Seville.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Gay Pride Week; Gays at the White House, 1977, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-178-1]; mp3 file; (Brief gap at 8:07 to 8:19 between multiple programs?. Discussion of Stonewall Riots and Gay Pride Week.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Franz Martin Interview (#156), 1976 August 26, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-179-1]; mp3 file; (Interview with Franz Martin discussing gay night life as well as discrimination within the gay community. Sounds as though there multiple recordings mashed together.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Women in Music I, 1980 December 18, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-180-1]; mp3 file; (Announcer Anna and various musical recordings, including: Baba Yaga "Old Woman", Holly Near, "Lady of the Piano", Alberta Hunter " Nobody Knows," "When You're Down and Out", "I'm Having a Good Time." Program discusses experiences of women coming out at different ages.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Women in Music II, 1980 December 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-181-1]; mp3 file; (Announcer of the Lesbian Radio Collective. Continuation of Barbara Smith's talk on her experiences with collations of black and white lesbians.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] "Emergency" Program, 1982 March 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-182-1]; mp3 file; (John Evola, announcer, with organizational information on how to get involved in Gay Rights Movement, popular music recordings, and a excerpt from the March on Washington.)
    - [Gayly Speaking Radio Program:] Unidentified, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel, 10.5 inch
      - [Part 1], [85287-SR-183-1]; mp3 file; (Announcers: Amy Fornier, Irene Mariposa. Theme of the program is "Revolution" consisting of poetry readings.)
    - Mager and Buckstaff on Obscenity April 7, 1977 (Box 9)
      (CD use copy available)
    - Speeches at the Militant Forum June 28, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Readings Undated (Box 9)
    - Theme Music Undated (Box 9)
    - Gay Pride Week; Gays at the White House Undated (Box 9)
    - Ralph and Alfred Undated (Box 9)
    - Women in Music I December 18, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Women in Music II December 25, 1980 (Box 9)
    - "Emergency" Program, aired March 11, 1982 (Box 9)
      (recorded December 12, 1980)
  - Miscellaneous
    - [Unidentified] Undated (Box 9)
    - Gay History Course 1979, 7 audiocassettes (Box 9)
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series (1982-1993, .6 linear feet) contains much of the fundraising and lobbying correspondence of M.O.H.R., as well as letters to and from individual members and non-members relating to the various social and political concerns of lesbians and gay men. The arrangement of the files as received from the donor has been retained; therefore, incoming and outgoing correspondence is separated for some years and not for others and some correspondence may be found in the Administrative and Topical series files.
  - 1982-1985 (Box 10)
  - 1986 (Box 10)
  - 1987 (Box 10)
  - 1988 (Box 10)
  - 1989, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Incoming 1990 (Box 10)
  - Outgoing 1990 (Box 10)
  - Incoming 1991 (Box 10)
  - Outgoing 1991 (Box 10)
  - Incoming 1992 (Box 10)
  - Outgoing 1992 (Box 10)
  - Incoming 1993 (Box 10)
  - Outgoing 1993 (Box 10)
- Paul T. McCullough Files
  - Organization structure 1987 (Box 10)
  - By-laws (Box 10)
  - Policy manual 1987 (Box 10)
  - Policies adopted 1987 (Box 10)